# TAHA RIZVI

# SR. GAME PROGRAMMER

6+ years of experience as game developer creating content on Unreal Engine and Unity using C++, blueprints and C#. Have extensive experience working on VR projects specifically. With a knack for team building and problem solving capablity to envision optimial solutions for team's success.



#### **CONTACT ME**

Email: taha.hassan110@gmail.com Cell: +49-176-46735728





# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

APR 2021 - PRESENT

#### SR. UNREAL DEVELOPER - REALWORLD ONE GMBH

- Developed state-of-the-art VR experiences in metaverse enviornment
- Design and implemented modular features and solutions
- Mentoring for juniors along with coordination with other dept.
- Involved in whole project's development life cycle

MAR 2020 - MAR 2021

#### SR. GAME PROGRAMMER - BITBUU GAMES

- Developed casual multiplayer mobile game as Hello Kitty offical game.
- Worked on game's new modular features
- Mentoring juniors and interns.
- · Worked on Gamespark backend, along with UI integrations.

FEB 2016- FEB 2020

#### VR/AR GAMEPLAY PROGRAMMER - REMATCH STUDIOS

- Developed full body VR character along with hand, foot and spine IK
- Developed gameplay elements such as puzzles, physical interactions, quick time events fights, dialogue system for NPC
- Source control management and training to technical art and content creation department
- Worked as firefighter, to solve bugs and provide required assistance

### **KEY SKILLS**

**ENGINES** Java **Unity Collaborate** 

**IDEs OTHER Unreal Engine 4** 

Unity Visual Studio **VR** Development

**SOFTWARES** Corona **ARCore** Photoshop **LANGUAGES** VuForia

**SOURCE CONTROL** Game Physics **Blueprints** 

Perforce C# **Project Management** 

Github C++Game Spark

# **INTERESTS**



MUSIC



**VR GAMING** 



**MOVIES** 





LEARNING **NEW SKILS** 

LATEST TECH

## ACHIEVEMENT AND AWARDS

#### **GOLD MEDALIST**

Institute of business administration, Karachi (2016)

#### WINNER PROGRAMMING COMPETITION

Developer's day, FAST University (2014)

#### PUBLISHED GAMES AND APPS

Area of darkness: Sentinel (VR) Globematcher, Sanrio blast, Super Air Hockey and more..

## **PROJECTS**

#### IKA MAGIC PLANT - VR INDUSTRIAL TRAINING

Unreal Engine | Blueprints | C++ | Rift | Multiplayer | RW1 platform

Industrial training in multiplayer enviornment, with mirroring mode as main feature, where items are mirrored on opposite table so trainer can explain to trainee.

#### AREA OF DARKNESS VR

Unreal Engine | Blueprints | C++ | Rift | Vive | WMR | Steam

Narrative FPS VR adventure game with full body IK and mechanics like physical bag inventory, interactive QTEs, choices that shape story.

#### **GLOBEMATCHER**

Unity | C# | Unity Collaborate | Gamespark | Firebase | Shader Programming | Playstore Fun and interactive casual mobile game developed specifically for mobile devices and used hello kitty characters as their official partner game.

#### CHECK OUT PORTFOLIO FOR MORE PROJECTS

Unreal Engine | Blueprints | C++ | Unity | C# | VR | AR | Multiplayer | PC | Mobile

Have worked on several freelance professional and personal projects, vary from hardcore FPS shooter game on PC to casual mobile games. Have extensive experience working on VR games and experiences.

# **EDUCATION**

FEB 2017 - DEC 2020

### MASTERS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Institute of business administration | Karachi

Courses: Software project management, Human computer interaction.

FEB 2012 - JAN 2016

#### **BACHELORS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE**

Institute of business administration | Karachi

Courses: Maths in games, Modelling and simulation, Data structures, OOP